# 大家好 現在那個母狗又生了哦 兩條母狗又生啦
Hi everyone! The dogs have given birth again, I mean the two female ones.
# 兩個六條哦 (註︰這裡我保留他不完整的句子)
Both six puppies.
# 加起來就12條
Together means twelve.
# 在這裡 就這裡
They're here, right here.
# 你看 這個小花狗
Look! This is a tinted puppy.
# 生了兩條花的
She has two tinted puppies.
# 這種顏色的
This colour...
# 你看 這種顏色的 不知道是誰的
Look! This colour. Whose babies can they be?
# 不是你的 不要看 你的在那邊
Don't watch! They're not yours. Yours are over there.
# 這個小黑
Naughty Blacky.
# 看一下這條 這條也是 這條也是花的哦
Have a look at this one. This one is also, this one is also tinted.
# 好胖哦
It's really fat!
# 這個好會帶崽
She takes very good care of her babies.
# 這個好會帶崽 這條(母狗)
This, this (mother) takes very good care of her babies.
# 這裡有6條哦 這裡
Here are six puppies, here.
# 123
One, two, three
# 誒
Eh~
# 還有呢
Where are the rest?
# 哦 還有在這裡
Oh! They're here.
# 全齊啦 6條都在這裡
All here. All six puppies are here.
# 這個小灰灰
This is a little greyie.
# 這邊這窩生了6隻
There are six puppies in this litter.
# 那邊 隔壁那邊又生啦
There, next door, is another litter.
# 生啦 也是生了6隻哦
There are, there are another six puppies.
# 我看一下 看一下那另一窩哦
Let me take a look, take a look at the other litter.
# 那窩在隔壁
They are next door.
# 你看 這3條是小黑的崽
Look! These three puppies are Blacky's babies.
# 肥的像豬一樣
They're as fat as pigs!
# 那麼肥啦 天天偷人家奶喝
You are so fat and you steal others' milk every day.
# 是不是 偷這條母狗的奶喝
Do you? It steal this mother's milk.
# 換一個 這隻
Next. This one
# 這個也是
This one too
# 這個你看 胖成這樣子啦
Have a look at this one! It's already that fat now.
# 是啊 還吃 你看
Really! But it still keeps on eating. Look!
# 又想吃 打你屁股 打你屁股
It wants to eat again. I spank you, spank you!
# 過來
Come here!
# 胖成這樣子
It's that fat now.
# 太胖啦 你兒子
Your son is just far too fat.
# 你兒子太胖 來吃點奶 吃你老媽的
Your son is too fat. Come and have some milk, from your own mom.
# 小黑到這裡來
Come to this side, Blacky.
# 坐下來
Sit down!
# 這個生的全是黑的
Her babies are all black.
# 你看這個又想去吃奶
Look! This one wants milk again.
# 小胖子不要去吃啦
Stop it, you chubby.
# 再吃 你就胖成不成樣啦 你看一下
Otherwise, you would as fat as a monster. Look!
# 現在都成這樣子啦 你還吃
You're already obese. But you still keeps on eating.
# 你看
Look!
# 是不是
Am I right?
# 怎麼可以這樣子
How can you be that fat?
# 這個也是 這個是最喜歡叫的
And this one too. This one yelps the most.
# 它這樣子 它就起不來了
Now it can't get up.
# 起來呀 你起來呀
Get up! C'mon get up!
# 起來
Get up!
# 嘿嘿 起不來啦
He he! It can't.
# 哎呦
Ayo?
# 胖的太胖啦
It's far too fat.
# 你看一下你
Have a look at yourself!
# 看一下你
# 它現在睜開眼睛 差不多可以下去玩啦
They have now opened their eyes. They can soon go down and have fun.
# 我們看一下小豬
Let's have a look at the piglets.
# 誒 那個是公的 這個是公的
Ey? Which one is male? This one is male.
# 哎呦 那麼凶
Ayo! It's so fierce.
# 這個公豬 這個公豬要把它閹啦
This boar, this boar has to be castrated.
# 這個是公豬哦 公豬要把它閹啦的[SIC]
This is a boar. A boar has to be castrated.
# 如果大閹掉 那個肉不好吃
Otherwise the pork won't taste good.
# 母豬別來 別來
Sow! Don't come! Don't come!
# 剛好叫兄弟過來
I've just asked my buddy to come here,
# 把它那個 把它抓住
to, you know, to catch it.
# 這個公豬要閹一下 這個是碘伏哦
The boar has to be castrated. This is povidone-iodine.
# 刀片
Blade
# 兄弟對不起啦 (註︰這個「兄弟」是指豬)
My apologies, little brother.
# 來 這裡
C'mon. Here.
# 好啦好啦 已經好啦
Alright! Alright! It's done.
# 可以啦 (把它閹好了) 閹好一隻 先閹一隻來試一下
Alright! It's castrated now. So I'm done with one. Let's see what happens to this one first.
# 不敢閹太多 等一太閹壞了 不好搞哦
Not too many at a time. Otherwise it would be too bad if something goes wrong.
# 那條稍微小一點的 它一直看著我
That one, the slightly smaller one, it keeps staring at me.
# 沒事的 不然長大了 你的肉又不好吃
No worries. Otherwise, when you grow up, your pork would taste awful.
# 那很麻煩的
And it would be a big headache.
# 它一直看著我
It keeps staring at me.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 回去玩啊
Have fun with you friends.
# 明天我看一下你的傷勢
I'll inspect your wound tomorrow.
# 如果沒問題的話 全部把你們 全部通通閹掉
If you are fine, I'll have you all, everybody, every single one, castrated.
# 第二天
The next day
# 你看 這條小豬是昨天閹的
Look! This is the piglet castrated yesterday.
# 你看現在甚麼事都沒有 哦 小豬
Look! It looks as if nothing has happened. Hey! Piglet!
# 小豬 過來 過來
Come here piglet! Come here!
# 過來~
I say come here!
# 摸一下你的鼻子
Let me touch your nose.
# 你看 甚麼事都沒啦 哦
Look! It's perfectly healthy, isn't it?
# 下次就輪到你 大公豬
It's your turn next time, big boar!
# 割你的
I'll cut yours.